Early Earth might have been very purple.
Today, plants on Earth look green
because they're turning sunlight into
energy using this molecule, chlorophyll,
which absorbs red and blue wavelengths
and reflects back green. But the way
that it does that is very complex. And
so, scientists think that Earth's
earliest organisms might have started
with something simpler, like this
molecule, retinol. Retinol can convert
sunlight into energy more directly. It's
not as effective at letting things grow
as chlorophyll, but it's enough to keep
things alive. But retinol absorbs green
wavelengths and reflects these other
parts, turning our oceans purple. And
we're using this idea to try to find
alien life. To see that, subscribe.